这真是个好主意
This was a good idea.
我们已经好久没举办闺蜜之夜了
It's been a long time since we've had girls' night.
对啊  能够有个放松的夜晚
Yeah, it's so nice to have a relaxing evening
在家什么都不干最棒了
at home doing nothing.
对啊  跟我这个月其他30个
Yeah, really breaks up the other 30 days
在家休养屁事不干的日子完全不同
I've spent on bed rest doing nothing.
今晚我们会让你忘掉那一切
Well, tonight we're gonna make you forget all that.
你们会让我忘记我被困床上
You're gonna make me forget I've been stuck in bed
还有小宝宝把我的膀胱当球踢吗
while a baby uses my bladder as a kickball?
你自己跟霍华德无套啪啪啪
Hey, you had unprotected sex with Howard.
你遭报应纯属活该
You deserve to be miserable.
我需要一点时尚建议
Hey, I need some fashion advice.
真的吗  向我请教啊  我很乐意...
Really? From me? I would love to...
其实是莱纳德跟我说佩妮在这里
Actually, Leonard told me Penny was over here?
怎么了  你要跟小妞约会吗
Hey, what's going on? You got a date?
我...  是跟科学有个约会
I, uh, do have a date... with science.
那科学会穿什么呢
Oh, what's science wearing?
格里菲斯天文台在找一名天体物理学家
The Griffith Observatory is looking for an astrophysicist
来当顾问  我明天要去面试
to consult, and I have an interview tomorrow.
我好喜欢那个天文台
Oh, I love the observatory.
他们会告诉你  你在别的星球时的体重
They tell you your weight on all the different planets.
金星的重力约是地球上的0.91
在金星时  永远都适合穿比基尼
Yeah. It's always bikini season on Venus.
我觉得你一定能胜任
I think you'd be great at that.
你也同意吧  伯纳黛特
Don't you agree, Bernadette?
啥  我有在听  我有在听
Huh? I'm listening. I'm listening.
我没有在看电视剧《王冠》
I'm not watching The Crown.
我就是想给人好的第一印象
I just want to make a good first impression,
所以想请你帮我挑一件好的
and thought maybe you could help me pick out an outfit?
没问题  让我看看
Of course. Let's see what you got.
其实你只需要选一件
Yeah, you just need to pick something
能让你感到自信的就行了
that-that you feel confident in.
抱歉  我没带我的自信魔法外套来
I'm sorry. I left my magic clothes at home.
我相信这两件就够...
I'm sure these two options will be f...
你...  你家还有别的衣服吗
So you-you have other clothes at home?
算啦  无所谓
Uh, it doesn't matter.
他们要跟一大堆人谈
They're talking to a bunch of people.
估计都选不上我
I probably won't get it anyway.
-别这么说  -对啊  你得对自己有自信
- Well, don't say that. - Yeah, you have to believe in yourself.
其实在我来美国之前
You know, before I came to America,
我是个很有自信的小伙子
I was filled with confidence.
我怎么会变成这样
What happened to me?
拉杰来你们闺蜜之夜吗
Hey, is that Raj there at girls' night?
你好啊  霍华德
Well, hey. Hey, Howard.
记住了  如果你先睡着
Just remember, if you fall asleep first,
少女过夜聚会的常见恶作剧
她们会把你的胸罩拿去冰箱冻住
they're gonna freeze your bra.
第十一季  第十集
你跟艾米计划婚礼还愉快吗
You and Amy having fun planning your wedding?
我们决定使用一种数学方法
We're employing a mathematical approach
叫决策论  所以...  太特么愉快了
called decision theory, so, heck, yeah.
"特么"吗
Heck, yeah?
某人得交一块钱的"接近骂脏话"罚款啊
Looks like someone need to put a dollar in the almost-swear jar.
我们随机分配所有需要下的婚礼决定
We've assigned all wedding decisions randomly,
然后我们一人决定一半
and each of us makes half of them.
比如婚礼场地  证婚人
You know, from venue to officiant
杜威十进制是美国最普遍的图书分类法
到宾客的桌号是用罗马数字还是杜威十进制
to numbering system for the tables: Roman or Dewey Decimal.
普遍应用在计算机领域
为什么不用十六进制数
Why not hexadecimal?
因为这是婚姻大事  不是相声大会
'Cause this is our wedding, not a joke.
-你们好啊  -你来啦
- Hey, guys. - ?Hello.
太好啦  经理拉杰来了
Oh, good. Raj is here
快告诉我们今天有哪些特餐
to tell us today's specials.
好笑好笑  我今天下午有个面试
Very funny. I have my interview this afternoon.
如果面试失败
Oh. If it doesn't work out,
摩门教传教士通常都是穿着西装传教
你也穿好可以去传摩门教的衣服啦
you're ready to go on your Mormon mission.
我没懂你们这是什么情况
I-I don't understand what's going on here.
情况就是呢
Oh, what's going on here is
我要去面试天文馆的一个工作
I'm up for a job at the planetarium,
而霍华德在吐槽我
and Howard is making fun of me.
那太好了  你们都在做自己爱做的事
Oh, that's great. You're both doing what you love.
我为你感到兴奋
Well, I'm excited for you.
谢谢  录用之后  天文馆所有的节目
Oh, thanks, yeah. I'd be in charge of developing
都将会由我来开发与念旁白
and narrating all the planetarium shows.
我很想要这份工作
And I really want this,
所以你多支持我一下是会死吗
so it wouldn't kill you to be more supportive.
如果死了  可以葬在你当入殓师的殡仪馆吗
But if it did, you could bury me at the funeral home you direct.
等等  哏都是在嘲讽他打扮跟平常不一样吗
Wait. The premise is that he is dressed differently?
对啊
Yeah.
的确啊  是跟平常差很多
That's true. He is not dressed the same.
爸
Hey, Dad.
你好啊  拉杰什
Hello, Rajesh.
面试怎么样了
How was the interview?
不是太好
Uh, not so great.
他们问我最大的缺点是什么
They asked me what my biggest weakness was,
45分钟后  他们谢谢我来参加面试
and 45 minutes later, they thanked me for coming.
儿子  爸不是不爱你  但你是有啥毛病啊
Son, don't take this the wrong way, but what's your problem?
我想回答你  但回答一次貌似需要45分钟
I would tell you, but apparently it takes 45 minutes.
其实呢
You know what?
我觉得你是受身边的朋友影响
I bet it's those friends you surround yourself with.
比如那个霍华德  总是在取笑你
Like that Howard, always making fun of you.
霍华德不是真心的啦
Howard doesn't mean anything by it.
我觉得是文化差异
I-I think it's cultural.
他的族群来自一个很毒舌的村子
His people come from a very sarcastic village
叫布鲁克林[黑人区]
called Brooklyn.
别为他找理由
Don't make excuses.
什么朋友会像他这样啊
What kind of friend acts that way?
我想...
Well, I-I guess...
我这是个反问句
It was a rhetorical question.
垃圾堆捡来的朋友才这样
A bad friend!
别这样  老爸  我跟他之间的关系就这样
Come on, Dad! That's just our relationship, okay?
他开印度人玩笑  我会笑一下
He makes Indian jokes, and I laugh,
但我眼神是生气的  让他知道这是不对的
but, you know, with angry eyes so he knows it's not okay.
我也有过一段
I, too, was in a relationship
跟总贬低我的人在一起的感情
with someone who made me feel bad about myself.
如果你是要说我妈  那我不要听
If you're talking about Mom, I don't want to hear it.
听我一说  如果你把霍华德
I'm just saying, if you replace Howard
换成一个如花似玉的22岁研究生
with a nice 22-year-old grad student,
你的自信绝对会爆棚
your self-confidence will soar.
好了  艾米  轮到你了
All right, Amy, you're up.
下一个决定
Next decision.
来吧  首支舞
Come on, first dance!
快来  首支舞
邀请函
Invitations!
这个也很不错啊
That's a good one.
纯给个建议
Just a suggestion--
由《星球大战》萌机器人放出全息投影
hologram projected out of R2-D2.
感谢您的意见  但这是我的决定
Thanks for your input, but this is my decision,
而我决定要...
and I'm gonna go with...
用古英文以书法写在埃及莎草纸上
old English calligraphy on Egyptian papyrus.
真是有趣的混合啊
Oh, what a fun mashup.
简直就像炸鸡华夫饼  毫不异端  毫不做作呢
It's like the chicken and waffles of orthography.
轮到你啦
Your turn.
戒童
Ring bearer!
妈呀  太庆幸刚才没把萌机器人用掉
Boy, I'm so glad that R2-D2 is still available.
其实这样挺好玩的呢
You know, this is really fun.
真不敢相信别人都说计划婚礼
I can't believe that people say that planning a wedding
是人生中压力最大的一件事之一
is one of the most stressful things in life.
对啊  从来没有过哪一天我不惊讶
I know. Not a day goes by that I don't marvel
我们能比别人强上那么多
how much better we are than other people.
面试不顺利我也很替你难过
I'm so sorry the interview didn't go well.
这工作真的很适合你呢
Yeah, you would've been perfect for it.
我就是会太紧张
Oh, I just get so nervous,
然后我又会为自己太紧张而道歉
and then I start apologizing for being nervous, and...
你们不会想听这个的  抱歉啦
You guys don't want to hear about this. I'm sorry.
别再道歉了好吗
Stop apologizing!
天啊
Oh, my God!
你说的简直跟面试那女士一样
You sound just like the woman at the interview!
你有想过去跟
Have you ever thought about talking
什么心理医生之类的谈这事吗
to some kind of therapist about all this?
或许吧
Ugh. Maybe.
莱纳德  你觉得你母亲会有空吗
Hey, Leonard, do you think your mom would be available?
你不会想找她谈的
Yeah, you don't want to do that.
想跟我妈聊天来得到信心
Talking to my mom to get more confidence
就跟去找阎王聊天来得到生存感一样
is like talking to a lion to get more alive.
我爸爸觉得
Well, my dad thinks
是因为霍华德总吐槽我害的
it's because Howard's always making fun of me.
这话有道理
Well, that makes sense.
你说这话有道理是什么意思
Well, what do you mean, that makes sense?
霍华德的确常常吐槽他
Well, Howard does make fun of him a lot.
那也不全是霍华德的错啊
Well, that's not all Howard's fault.
要是拉杰不想被吐槽  那我...
I mean, if Raj doesn't want to be made fun of, then I...
我不知道要怎么礼貌地结束这句话
Hmm. I don't know a nice way to finish this sentence.
这么说你站在他那边
Well, so you're on his side?
我只是说
I'm just saying,
朋友之间就是这样  互相怼的啊
that's what friends do. You know, they bust on each other.
那些话并不代表什么啊
It doesn't mean anything.
我不意外你这么想
Well, I'm not surprised you think so.
为什么
Why is that?
你对我也挺毒舌的
Well, you can be kind of mean to me.
那是因为你是...
Well, that's because you're...
这句话我也不知道该怎么收尾
Wow. I don't know how to finish that sentence, either.
你知道吗  我们俩都受够了不被尊重
You know what? I think we're both done being disrespected.
我还有几口气  还能再承受羞辱
I got a few rounds left in me.
英勇的好小伙
Attaboy, champ.
看看目前我们都有什么了
Okay, let's see what we've got so far.
我坐在美剧《草原小屋》风的马车上入场
I arrive in a Little House on the Prairie style horse-drawn buggy.
再由《星球大战》暴风兵仪仗队员迎接
Where you are met with an honor guard of stormtroopers.
你会不会觉得有点风格不搭
Do you think that might be jarring,
从健康的拓荒者跳到太空纳粹
going from wholesome pioneers to space Nazis?
我懂你意思了
I see what you're saying.
你在想  你入场时应该乘坐
You're thinking that you should arrive
仿制的《星球大战》卢克·天行者的陆行艇
in a replica of Luke Skywalker's landspeeder.
我不是在想这个
It's not what I'm thinking,
顺便帮你省去以后的麻烦
and to save you the trouble for the future,
我此生都不会有这想法
it will never be what I'm thinking.
如果迎宾员对你那么重要
Well... if the ushers are so important to you,
那我们做笔交易如何
what if I propose a trade?
让你选迎宾员  而第一支舞就由我来决定
You may pick that, and I will decide, say, first dance.
好极了  那迎宾员就由
Great. Then the ushers will be...
我穿上拓荒者双排扣长外套的表妹们担当
my cousins dressed in frontier frock coats.
那第一支舞就  不跳了
And the first dance will be that we won't have one.
好吧  那我们的
All right. Then our...
第二支舞就变成第一支舞了
second dance will be the first dance.
我们取消跳舞环节就行啦
Unless we have no dance at all.
呵呵
Ha-ha.
如果要做出改变
Well, if we're changing things,
那我们不要扔彩纸屑
then instead of throwing confetti,
改成放蝴蝶吧
we'll release butterflies.
空中乱飞的虫子  你疯了吗
Airborne worms?! Have you lost your mind?!
如果你要这么做
Well, if you're going to do that,
我就把证婚人换成
then I am changing the officiant to that
常在中国剧院出没的大只佬蜘蛛侠
husky Spider-Man that hangs out at the Chinese Theater.
行啊  婚礼祝酒词换成拉丁语的
Fine. Wedding toasts in Latin.
好极了  婚誓用克林贡语说
Great. Vows in Klingon.
那我要把女花童换成狗
Then I'm changing the flower girl to a dog.
你猜这下他不撒花瓣  而是撒什么
And guess what he'll be scattering instead of petals!
想去吃午饭吗
Want to grab some lunch?
你猜怎么着  不去
You know what? I don't think so.
我来猜猜看  你不吃饭
Well, let me guess. You're not eating
是因为刻薄女们用笔把你胖的部位圈出来了
because the mean girls circled your chubby bits in marker?
不  是这个  你刚才说的这个  这就是原因
No. That. That right there. That's the reason.
你总是在取笑我
You're always making fun of me.
那些都是玩笑话而已
Oh, those are just jokes.
我用这种方式来表达我们是朋友
It's my way of saying that we're friends,
再说你减个几斤又不会死
and it wouldn't hurt you to drop a few!
看到没  难怪我没自信
See? No wonder I don't have any confidence.
不是吧  这怎么能怪在我头上
Come on. You can't blame that on me.
为什么不能  15年来你不断地奚落我
Why not? 15 years of constant ridicule.
我觉得我们的关系已经变得有毒了
I-I think our relationship has become toxic.
你这是什么意思
Uh, what are you saying?
我觉得我们需要分开一段时间
I think you and I need to spend some time away from each other.
听着  我看得出你不开心  但是...
Look, I... I can see you're upset, but...
我需要知道一些基本规则
I'm gonna need some ground rules. I mean,
分开期间  我能否约其他缠人的印度男
while we're apart, can I see other needy Indian men?
滚出去
Get out!
你们觉得哪个会毁掉艾米心中的婚礼
What do you think will make the wedding worse for Amy:
把结婚蛋糕从甜的改成咸的
a cake made with salt instead of sugar...
还是把蛋糕的糖霜改成凝固的肉汁
...or a cake iced with congealed gravy?
这是陷阱答案
That is a trick question.
正解是  你当新郎
The answer is: you as the groom.
不会真的做刚才说的蛋糕
Neither of them will be the actual cake.
我只是用这个来要挟
I'm just using it as a bargaining chip
逼艾米同意  让每个宾客都得到一枚戒指
to get Amy to agree to the whole wedding party getting rings
电影《指环王》的剧情
我们则得到一枚可以统治他们的至尊戒
and us getting one ring to rule them all.
我忘了  你俩是住在哪间精神病院来着
I forget, which mental hospital are you guys registered at?
大家好
Hello.
-你们好啊  -好啊
- Hello. - ?Hello.
不是吧你
Really?
你不坐这里吗
You're not gonna sit here?
等你走了  我就过去坐
I'll sit there as soon as you leave.
你还没气完吗  我道过歉了
You're still on this? I said sorry.
道歉也不能弥补多年来对我的精神虐待
Well, "sorry" doesn't make up for years of emotional abuse.
那你要怎样才不气了
Well, what's it gonna take?
我分半个三明治给你行吗
You want half my sandwich?
这是什么情况
What is going on?
拉杰想把他可悲的人生怪到我头上
Raj is trying to blame me for his pathetic life.
他的生活才不可悲
His life isn't pathetic.
他能独占一整张桌子不用跟别人分呢
He's got that whole table to himself.
我俩应该有一个过去陪拉杰坐
One of us should go sit with Raj so he's not alone.
但我还没说完我的婚礼复仇计划呢
But I'm not done telling you about my wedding revenge plans.
也对  继续说吧
You're right. Go on.
好咧  首先我要尝试
Okay, well, first, I'm going to try
让艾米跟我换餐前冷盘的选择权
to get Amy to trade with me for hors d'oeuvres...
太好了  你在家
Oh, good, you're here.
我已经决定了餐桌中央的摆饰
I've decided on our centerpieces.
希望你的家人不会对石棉[有害]过敏
I just hope your family isn't allergic to asbestos.
谢尔顿  拜托你住手吧
Sheldon, please stop.
再这样下去  到时的婚礼
If we keep doing this, we're gonna end up with a wedding
我们两人都不会喜欢的
that neither one of us will enjoy.
你意思是你不想结婚了吗
Are you saying you don't want to get married?
不  我当然想结
No, of course I do.
但我们能意见一致的部分  也就仅此而已了
But that seems to be the one thing we can agree on.
也许我们去市政厅登记一下就好了
Maybe we should just get married at City Hall
不安排婚礼那些的了
and forget about everything else.
市政厅
City Hall, hmm.
我确实喜欢金属探测器
I do like metal detectors
和许可证被拒绝时的响声
and the sound of permits being denied.
对啊
Right.
如果我们根本不享受计划过程
And if we're not enjoying planning this wedding,
那办婚礼还有什么意义呢
then what's the point?
从历史上来讲  婚礼是为了
Well, historically, a wedding was to let
让其他潜在追求者知道  我们有主了
other potential suitors know that we're unavailable.
但我觉得上面印着
But I think matching T-shirts that say
"眼看手勿动"的情侣装T恤也有这功能
"hands off the merchandise" accomplish the same thing.
我们就选个日子去登记吧
So let's pick a day and just go do it.
明天怎么样
How 'bout tomorrow?
真的吗
R-Really?
这么快
That soon?
何必等呢
Why wait?
我是不认为我们活在婚前同居的罪恶中啦
I mean, it's not that I think we're living in sin,
但我也想我们下次的亲密行为
but I do like the idea that our next act of intimacy
是受法律要求的
will be a legal requirement.
明天我们就去市中心登记结婚
Tomorrow we'll go downtown and get married.
或者如果你想旅行结婚
Or we could go to Beverly Hills City Hall
我们可以去比弗利山庄的市政厅
if you want a destination wedding.
你今天很帅气
Hey. You look good today.
怎么了  出什么事了
What happened? What's wrong?
你就直说吧  我扛得住
Just tell me. I can take it.
没什么  我觉得自己经常损你好坏
Nothing. I felt bad about being mean to you,
所以就想对你好点
so I'm being nice.
好吧  不好意思  刚才没准备好
Oh, okay. Sorry. I wasn't ready for it.
再说一次
Try again.
你看起来很帅
You look handsome.
不行  还是让我心慌慌
Nope, still freaking me out.
亲们好啊
Hello, friends!
你的头发怎么了
Hey, what's going on with your hair?
没什么  只是决定不再拉直了
Uh, nothing. I just decided to stop straightening it.
等等  你之前发型居然是故意弄的吗
Wait, so you were making your hair look like that on purpose?
我刚搬到美国时  想融入大家
When I first moved to America, I wanted to fit in.
而霍华德的头发是直的
And Howard's hair was straight,
当时他是我认识的最酷的人
and he was the coolest person I knew.
之后你再没见过其他人类了吗
Then you never saw any other people?
其实  我不想提起霍华德了
You know what, I-I don't want to talk about Howard.
我是来庆祝的
I came here to celebrate!
没错  我回去天文馆告诉他们
Yeah. I went back to the planetarium and told them
他们犯了天大的错  我非常适合这份工作
they were making a huge mistake, that I'd be perfect for the job.
我当时很讨人喜欢  自信满满
I was... I was charming, I was confident.
于是他们就要我了
And they gave it to me.
太棒了
That's amazing!
还有就是  他们之前招聘的那个人
Yeah, plus, it turns out the guy they hired
做"保健"被抓了
got busted at a sketchy massage parlor.
这下你也是满足了
Oh, so happy ending for you!
那人应该也"满足"了
Oh, and for him.
我本来要去告诉霍华德
Yeah, I was on my way to tell Howard,
然后想起来我和他吵架呢
and then I remembered I wasn't speaking to him,
所以就过来了
so I came over here.
-你不觉得你俩应该和好了吗  -才怪
- Mm, don't you think it's time you two made up? ?- No.
现在的我才不需要他的负能量
No, actually. I don't need his negative energy in my life right now.
反抗他虽然不容易
Standing up to him was-was hard,
但这让我发现  我可以做到任何事
but it made me realize that I can do anything.
虽然有一点小悲伤  但是  你懂的
And, yeah, it's a little sad, but, you know,
人生就是...
life is all about...
抱歉
Uh, sorry.
我以为你差不多说完了
I thought you were wrapping things up.
-霍华德  -嗨
- Hey, Howard. ?- Hey.
其他人呢
Where is everybody?
我可以问你同样的问题
I could ask you the same question.
这段对话立马就变刻薄了
Wow, this conversation got mean fast.
抱歉  我现在心情不好
Sorry. I'm just in a bad mood.
是吗  怎么了
Yeah? What's going on?
我和拉杰吵架了
I had a falling out with Raj.
他说我太常取笑他
He said I make fun of him too much
打击坏了他的自信
and it's wrecked his confidence.
拜托  自信心就像红血球一样
Please, confidence is like red blood cells--
有当然好  但你并不需要它们
it's nice if you got some, but you don't need 'em.
对啊  你的人生也一团糟啊
Yeah. I mean, your life's a mess.
我也没见你怪在别人头上
I don't see you blaming other people for it.
是啊  我出生在一个充满爱和支持的家庭中
That's right. I grew up in a loving, supportive household.
走到这步  只能怪我自己
This is all on me.
我还是自己先转转吧
Maybe I'll just hang out here for a while.
太好了  你也可以尽情地取笑我
Great. And you can make fun of me all you want.
不  还是算了
No, that's okay.
不  不  没关系  我受得住
No, no, no. Go on. I can take it.
我的感情  就和我的四肢一样
My feelings, like my extremities,
基本上是麻木的
are basically numb.
这是你们的证书
Here's your license.
现在  你俩在这里等一下
Now, if you wait over there,
等证婚人准备好了我就叫你们
we'll call you when the officiant's ready.
我们需要验血吗
Do we need a blood test?
不需要
No.
这样的话你怎么知道我俩有没有梅毒呢
Well, then, how will you know whether or not we have syphilis?
我就大胆假设你没有吧
I'm gonna go out on a limb and say you don't have that.
谢尔顿  你已经正式用完了我能忍受
Okay, Sheldon, you officially exceeded the number of times
在大喜之日上听到"梅毒"这个词的次数了
I hoped to hear the word "syphilis" on my wedding day.
我真不敢相信我们要这么做了
I can't believe we're doing this.
我知道  我们要结婚了
I know. I'm getting married.
新的《星球大战》电影要上映了
The new Star Wars movie's coming out.
这个年末真是过得好精彩
We are really finishing this year strong.
好吧  但在这两者之中...
Okay, but of the two of tho...
算了  我不问  我不问
You know, I'm not even gonna ask. I'm not gonna ask.
你会因为我们没有举办盛大婚礼而难过吗
Are you sad we're not having a big party?
我真的没有
I'm really not.
我们一同在这里  已经很完美了
I'm here with you. It's perfect.
库珀-福勒
Cooper-Fowler?
该你们了
You're up.
你能相信吗
Can you believe it?
我们即将作为库珀博士和福勒博士  走进去
We're about to walk in that door, Dr. Cooper and Dr. Fowler,
等我们出来就是新婚燕尔的
and walk out as a married couple,
库珀博士和福勒博士
Dr. Cooper and Dr. Fowler.
等等
Wait.
我想和你跳婚礼上的第一支舞
I want to have a first dance with you.
就在这儿吗
Right here?
在我们的婚礼上
At our wedding.
这就是我们的婚礼呀
Th-This is our wedding.
不
No.
我想要一场真的婚礼
I want a real wedding.
可是...
Well...
谢尔顿  计划婚礼只会让我俩吵架
Sheldon, it was just making us fight.
我知道  艾米  可是
I know. But, Amy,
我从未想过有一天会与人结婚
I never thought I'd want to marry anyone.
所以我能找到你简直就是奇迹了
So the fact that I found you is astonishing.
这就好比找到暗物质
It's-it's like finding dark matter,
不同的是  科学家是很认真在寻找暗物质
except they're looking for dark matter.
而我都没有在找你
I wasn't even looking for you.
所以你是比暗物质更美好的存在
S-So you're even better than dark matter.
谢尔顿
Sheldon.
而且  而且你和光相互作用  所以我能看到你
Plus, plus, you interact with light, so I can see you.
另外  宇宙中那些消失的物质也跟你无关
And, also, you don't account for the missing mass in the universe.
-还有...  -我想你在我和暗物质的不同点上
- Oh, and... - Okay, I think you're getting caught up
陷入了死循环
on the ways I'm not like dark matter.
你说得对  抱歉
Right. Sorry.
但当一个人有了如此重大的发现
But when you make a discovery like this,
他不该静悄悄地带它去市政厅
you don't just take it down to City Hall--
而是会站出来告诉全世界
you tell the whole world.
我会用拉丁文和克林贡语说一遍
And so I'll say it in Latin or Klingon
或者是用狼烟信号
or-or smoke signals,
如果不会对原住民文化不敬的话
if-if that's not cultural appropriation.
会的
It is.
好吧  那就不用狼烟
Okay, so not smoke signals.
但我想把这件事做好
But I want to do this right.
我也是
Me, too.
那就让我们来计划一场婚礼吧
Let's go plan a wedding.
其实呢  我们都穿戴整齐
You know, we did get dressed up
而且大老远来到了市政厅了
and come all the way to City Hall.
你想干什么
What are you thinking?
人家一直想搞一张处置危险废弃物的许可证
I have always wanted a permit to dispose of hazardous waste.
一起去吧
Let's do it.
土卫二的甲烷大气中  或是木卫二的冰川下
Do we know if there's life in the methane plumes of Enceladus
是否有我们已知的生命存在呢
or under the icy surface of Europa?
我将在下周二的节目中揭晓  不见不散
Come back on Tuesday for my next show to find out.
小小剧透  答案是没有
Spoiler alert: we don't.
我是拉杰什·库萨帕里博士
I'm Dr. Rajesh Koothrappali,
感谢你和我一起漫步在星空中
and thank you for taking a walk with me through the stars.
我从来都不知道科学也能这么有趣呢
Wow. I never knew science could be so interesting.
我不是常有和你聊科学吗
Hey, I talk to you about science all the time.
对啊  小宝贝
Oh, you sure do, sweetie.
我们应该过去祝贺他吗
Should we go congratulate him?
我有更好的主意  我要给他提些建设性意见
I'll do better than that-- I'll give him constructive criticism.
我给你一个建设性意见  别提
Here's some constructive criticism: don't.
-我一会儿来找你们  -好的
- I'll catch up with you guys. - ?Okay.
-拉杰  你真是太厉害了  -谢谢  我好紧张
- Raj, you were terrific! - Oh, thank you. I was so nervous,
我腋下湿得一塌糊涂
my armpits are like a swamp.
给你的拥抱正式降级为击掌了
Oh, your hug just got downgraded to a high five.
你的手心也全是汗呀
Your palms are sweaty, too.
你一个人在后面干什么呢
What are you doing all the way in the back?
我躲在这里呢
Hiding out.
不知道他是否欢迎我来
I wasn't sure if I was welcome.
别傻了  你们是死党
This is ridiculous. You guys are best friends.
他当然想你来了
Of course he wants you here.
你确定吗  没有我他一切也挺顺利的
You sure? He seems to be doing pretty well without me.
他当时只是烦到理智线断了
Look, he was just stressed out.
没有你  他的生活并没有变好
His life is not better without you.
过来吧  来打个招呼
Come on. Come say hi.
好吧
Okay.
库萨帕里博士  我只想为你刚才的表现点赞
Dr. Koothrappali, I just wanted to tell you that was amazing.
-我想反驳  -上车去了
- Uh, counterpoint... ?- To the car.
我能问你个问题吗
Can I ask you a question?
当然可以
Of course you can.
哎哟  我回答得不错
Ooh, that went well.
再问我一个
Ask me another.
我想我还是走吧
I think I'm just gonna go.
如果那些星球的地表下真的有生命
If there is life beneath the surface of these planets,
我们怎样才能发现他们呢
how would we even detect it?
这是个非常复杂的问题
Uh, that's a complicated question.
那我先换一个简单的问题吧
Let me start with a simpler one.
我能请你喝咖啡吗
Can I buy you a coffee?
这也是个复杂的问题
A-Also a complicated question.
因为我想答应你  可如果我现在喝了咖啡
Because I want to say yes, but if I drink coffee this late,
那今晚就别想睡了
then I'll be up all night.
脱因咖啡啊  天才
Decaf, genius.
我很愿意
I would love to.